Hakan Aksuman

İzmir, Turkey

h.aksuman@gmail.com

+90 553 158-81-66

linkedin.com/in/hakanaksuman

https://github.com/haksuman

Summary

I am currently working for United Nations as a Front-end developer and interested in coding for developing user interfaces on the web. Coding had been a hobby in my university years, which turned into passion driving me to enhance my knowledge about responsive web design. Since I am an attentive self-learner and flexible selfstarter, I always implement and improve practical skills about programming. Swiftly responding changing needs of an organization, quick self-learning, experience with React & Typescript, strong communication and interpersonal skills are abilities which underpin me as a Front-end developer.

Experience



Frontend Developer

United Nations

Jul 2022 - Present (2 months +)

Front-end design of the United Nations' radar and user interface

- Developed front-end user interface by using React and Typescript
- Participate in the analysis of initial issues and goals
- Implement the features and user interfaces of new and existing products with JavaScript- Streamlined software development testing practices throughout the team.
- Managed version control operation operations with Git.



Data Analyst

United Nations

May 2022 - Jul 2022 (3 months)

Al powered Knowledge Base Development

- Web scraping to various domains for knowledge-based AI development by using Python Beautifulsoup
- Developed automated headless web application tests with Selenium-webdrive.
- Performed data cleaning operations for obtained data with Numpy and Pandas.



Project Control Engineer

Renaissance Heavy Industries

Jun 2021 - Present (1 year 3 months +)

Arctic LNG-2 / Murmansk, Russia

- Creating data pipelines and connections with big data sets
- Automated reporting progress by developing automated reports with Python and Power BI
- Developed automated file management tools and slash required time for foldering by 85%

Skills

- Team Management
 Front-End Development
 Data Analysis
 React.js
 JavaScript
- Python • HTML • CSS • Software Development • Responsive Web Design

Education



Orta Doğu Teknik Üniversitesi / Middle East Technical University

Bachelor's degree, Civil Engineering

GPA: 3 20/4 00